Roberto Freire

Student of Computer Systems at British Columbia Institute of technology

robertofreire@hotmail.com

Summary

I have over 7 years of I.T. experience, my greatest strength is my ability to walk into a new environment and be functional immediately. I am eager to learn and to adapt to new situations, configurations and technologies. I am skilled Help Desk technician with over 5 years of experience providing PC and Client/Server tech support for small to medium sized businesses. Experienced diagnosing, troubleshooting and resolving client issues with Windows OS and Microsoft applications, OS X and applications, virtualized environments and hardware maintenance, installations and upgrades. Experienced in technical call center operations providing service by communicating effectively with technical and non-technical staff respecting the procedures to reflect ITIL best practices.

Experience

I.T. Specialist at hyperWALLET Systems Inc.

July 2013 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Providing end-user support for computer desktops, peripheral, and IT services by

- installing, monitoring, diagnosing, repairing, maintaining and upgrading desktop hardware, software, and peripheral equipment to ensure optimal workstation performance.

Providing customer-focused desktop support for staff.

Maintaining inventory, develop hardware specifications, and other administrative tasks.

Recording and tracking support request using ticket tracking system.

Working with VOIP supplier providing local technical support for the office VOIP system

Creating documentation for existing and new applications and procedures

Windows and Unix Technical Support Representative at Webserve Canada

October 2012 - May 2013 (8 months)

- Providing phone, email technical support
- Assisting other staff with projects related to Server Management and deployment.
- Analyze equipment performance records in order to determine the need for repair or replacement.
- Perform data backups and disaster recovery operations.
- Physical network cabling, Cisco Switches, routers, hubs.
- Maintain and administer computer networks and related computing environments, including computer hardware, systems software, applications software, and all configurations.
- Hosting administration, ASP Services and IIS.
- Gather data pertaining to customer needs, and use the information to identify, predict, interpret, and evaluate system and network requirements.
- Monitor network performance in order to determine whether adjustments need to be made, and to determine where changes will need to be made in the future.

- Maintain logs related to network functions, as well as maintenance and repair records.
- Maintain an inventory of parts for emergency repairs.

Senior Technical Consultant at Melange

December 2009 - May 2013 (3 years 6 months)

- Providing Service Desk support to customers, assisting them with hardware and software problems via phone, email and/or remotely.
- Maintenance of assigned servers, assisting with specified projects
- Diagnose hardware and software problems, and replace defective components of onsite systems
- Maintain and administer computer networks and related computing environments, including computer hardware, systems software, applications software, and all configurations.
- Plan, coordinate, and implement network security measures in order to protect data, software, and hardware.
- Perform routine network startup and shutdown procedures, and maintain control records.
- Design, configure, and test computer hardware, networking software and operating system software.
- Recommend changes to improve systems and network configurations, and determine hardware or software requirements related to such changes.
- Confer with network users about how to solve existing system problems.
- Train people in computer system use.
- Maintain logs related to network functions, as well as maintenance and repair records.

DBA at Telemar Norte Leste

September 2007 - September 2008 (1 year 1 month)

- Maintains data storage and access by designing physical databases
- Providing analyses Qualitatives and Quantitatives.
- Import & Export of various data formats using DTS
- Database Backup, Recovery and Disaster Recovery Procedures.
- Fraud Prevention

Tech Support at Assembleia legislativa do Estado de Minas Gerais

August 2005 - August 2007 (2 years 1 month)

- Java programming
- Script creation
- Database maintenance
- User support
- Diagnose, troubleshooting and repair hardware, server, software and network problems

Tech Support at CONAB - Companhia Nacional do Abastecimento

January 2006 - January 2007 (1 year 1 month)

Hardware Inventory and reports

Windows and linux Server Administration

Tech Support

Workstation setup, virtualization

Backup routine

Projects

Iphone Development

March 2011 to Present

Members:Roberto Freire, Richard Hart

Academic Control

Courses

Independent Coursework

ITIL Foundation ITI597

Languages

English (Professional working proficiency)

Portuguese (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Spanish (Professional working proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

SQL Server

Active Directory

Xcode

Objective-C

Java

VMware

LogMeIn

Virtualization

ABAP

SAP R/3

Windows 7

Windows Server

Portuguese

Eclipse

HTML + CSS

Computer Hardware

System Administration

TCP/IP

Network Topology

DNS administration

Network Administration

NAT

DHCP

WiMAX

iPhone development

IIS

Servers

Operating Systems

VMware ESX

VPN

Network Security

Unix

Switches

Routers

Group Policy

Troubleshooting

System Deployment

Windows

Hardware

Technical Support

Network Design

Software Installation

Red Hat Linux

Networking

Linux

Linux System Administration

ITIL

Firewalls

Disaster Recovery

Nagios

Education

British Columbia Institute of Technology

2013, Computer Systems Technology, 2011 - 2013

Activities and Societies: Bussiness and Technical communication, correspondences, and reports, Mathematics, Java Application Development, C++, Computer Architeture, System analysis and Design UML, .NET, Windows Server 2008, and Iphone Development

ILSC Language School

Language School, English, 2008 - 2009

Centro Universitário Newton Paiva

I.T., Computer Science, 2005 - 2008

Activities and Societies: Algorithms and data structures, Java Development, Database, Operational Systems, systems development methodology, Web, Computer Networks, Law over the internet and New tecnologies

Roberto Freire

Student of Computer Systems at British Columbia Institute of technology

robertofreire@hotmail.com



Contact Roberto on LinkedIn